Robert S. Phillips Papers
Robert S. Phillips Papers
- Writings
  - Stories
    - "The Girl with the Beautiful Clothes", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Granny Falk's Planting Time", typescript ms.; See also "The Planting Time of Granny Falk" (Box 27A)
    - "The Hateful Word", holograph ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Hateful Word", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Help", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Holiday Letter", holograph, typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Hot Dogs and Baked Beans", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Imperfect Heart" (collection)
      - Typescript ms. (Box 27A)
      - Typescript ms., 3 folders (Box 27A)
    - "In a Country of Strangers", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "In the New World", typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 27A)
    - "Incident in the Young Life of George Oliver Weatherbee", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Is Celeste There?", holograph, typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Isabella's Time", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Jackhammer", holograph, typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Jeopardy"
      - Holograph ms. (Box 27A)
      - Typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Jones Boy", typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 27A)
    - "The Kill-Joy", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "A Lady of Fashion", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Land of Lost Content", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Last Straw", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Lessons Learned", holograph ms. (Box 27A)
    - "A Little Night Music", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Loss", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Lost and the Found", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Lost Child", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "Magic, Parsimony, Witch & Wheels: Links in a Chain", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Man Who Read Proust", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Man with the Wooden Legs", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Mark", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "The Mask", typescript ms. (Box 27A)
    - "May Day", holograph, typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 27A)
    - "Mealy Marshall and the Whore of Babylon"
      - Typescript ms. (Box 28)
      - The Southern Humanities Review (Box 28)
    - "Messages", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Mistaken Rapture", holograph, typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Mr. Brown", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Mister Mercedes", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Mister Mercury", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Moon Pictures"
      - Holograph ms. (Box 28)
      - Typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "News About People You Know", holograph and typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Night Flowers", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Note Found in a Country Church", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "On the Way Home", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "An Orange from Mrs. Julian", typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - "The Outsider", holograph, typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "[The] Paper Bag", typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - "A Period Piece", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Piano Lessons", holograph ms. (Box 28)
    - "The Planting Time of Granny Falk", typescript ms.; See also "Granny Falk's Planting Time"; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - "The Presentation", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "The Projectile", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "The Red Notebook", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Rejections", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Requiem for a Cat", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Revenge", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Rise Up Singing", holograph ms. (Box 28)
    - "Rose Hill", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Sandra's Day", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Sensitivity Training"
      - Holograph ms. (Box 28)
      - Typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "The Shoes", typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - "So Long the Summer", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Soliloquy of a Bench Sitter", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Something Miraculous", holograph ms. (Box 28)
    - "Songs of Four Seasons", typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - "The Soul of Discretion", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Subscriptions, Salve, Grand Margaret and Ted Mack", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Sunday Morning", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Sundays", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Surprise", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "The Tale of a Tail", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Ten Letters", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "There Are Hospitals in New Jersey", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Three Encounters and a Postscript", typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - "Three Voices"
      - Holograph ms. (Box 28)
      - Typescript ms., 2 folders (Box 28)
    - "To Teddy", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Trepidation", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Two Encounters", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "The Very Same Spring", typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - "The Visitation", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "The Visitation", holograph ms. (Box 28)
    - "Wednesday Morning", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Wheels"
      - Holograph ms. (Box 28)
      - Typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Willard", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Wolfey", holograph ms. (Box 28)
    - "The Wounded Angel", holograph ms. (Box 28)
    - "Wunderkind", typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Untitled ("Even in appearance, Priscilla Potter ..."), typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - "Untitled ("Fallick is opening his mail ..."), holograph ms. (Box 28)
    - Untitled ("My name is Harry Simmons"), typescript ms. (Box 28)
    - Untitled ("We're returning home now, Minerva ..."), typescript ms. (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Audio and video cassettes
      - Interviews by R. Phillips
        - William Goyen, 2 cassettes (Box 29)
        - James Laughlin, 2 cassettes (Box 29)
        - Karl Jay Shapiro, 2 cassettes (Box 29)
        - William Jay Smith, 2 cassettes (Box 29)
      - Readings
        - "Bob Phillips at Mausoleum 9-20-00" (Box 29)
        - "Bonding" / by R. Phillips (with "Can You Ever Forgive Me?" / by Molly Giles) The Sound of Writing XI no. 122 (Box 29)
        - "Robert Phillips at Book Stop 1-22-99" (Box 29)
        - "Robert Phillips at Rudolph ? Gallery May 1999" (Box 29)
        - "San Miguel Poetry Week 1-5-00" (Box 29)
      - Speeches
        - "The Ming Vase of Poetry Reading Series': 25 Years at the Katonah Village Library" (Box 29)
        - "Phillips on Karl Shapiro Blauberin (Germany) 1994" (Box 29)
    - Biographical profiles for Dictionary of American Biography
      - Maxwell Geismar, research material, ms. (Box 29)
      - John Hall Wheelock, research material, typescript ms. (Box 29)
    - Biographical profiles for The Oxford Companion to 20th Century Poetry in English, typescript ms. (Box 29)
    - Biographical sketches for The Scribner's Encyclopedia of American Lives, holograph, typescript ms. (Box 29)
    - Biographical sketches for Who's Who in Twentieth Century World Poetry (Routledge), holograph, typescript ms. (Box 29)
    - Contemporary Authors Autobiography Series, autobiographical essay
      - Holograph ms. (Box 29)
      - Typescript ms. (Box 29)
      - Typescript ms., copyedited (Box 29)
      - Galleys (Box 29)
    - Debbie McIntosh ms. (unpublished) (Box 29)
    - Introduction to The Light in the Piazza and Other Italian Tales / by Elizabeth Spencer (Box 29)
    - "A Memorial Tribute to Karl Shapiro", program ms., and text of Introduction (Box 29)
    - Modern Poetry Studies special Horace Gregory issues (edited by R. Phillips), typescript ms.; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Panel discussion on first novels - Wesleyan Writers' Conference, 1991; holograph notes (Box 29)
- Memorabilia
  - Printed material
    - Programs, announcements, miscellaneous (Box 30)
    - Periodicals (issues of various publications in which R. Phillips' work has appeared)
      - By title A-B (Box 31)
      - By title Ca-Ch (Box 32)
      - By title Ci-E (Box 33)
      - By title F-H (Box 34)
      - By title I-M (Box 35)
      - By title N (Box 36)
      - By title O-P (Box 37)
      - By title R-Sn (Box 38)
      - By title So-Sz (Box 39)
      - By title T-Z (Box 40)